http://www.nln.org/about/privacy-policy

Quicklinks
About NLN Academic/Professional Progression in Nursing Academy of Nursing Education Accreditation (NLN CNEA) Accreditation Standards ACE Series ACE.C ACE.D ACE.P ACE.S ACE.V ACE.Z Advanced Practice in Nursing Advanced Advanced Practice Nursing Education Advancement of the Science of Nursing Education, NLN Chamberlain University College of Nursing Center for Affiliated Constituent Leagues Agency Search Aging Alzheimer’s Ambassador Program ANEF APIN Applications, Membership Associate Membership Awards Beverly Malone Bio Blog, NLN Nursing EDge Board of Governors
Books Calendar of Events Career Center Caregiving Centers of Excellence Program CEO Bio Certification for Nurse Educators CEUs CNE Application CNE Exam CNE®cl CNEA Coaching for Excellence Commission for Nursing Education Accreditation Competencies Conferences Constituent Leagues Contact Us Continuing Education Units Copyright Permissions Core Values Coronavirus Resource Center DataView Education Summit Elected Positions Elections Employment Ethics Events Excellence Model Faculty Compensation Faculty Development Bulletin Faculty Membership Faculty Preparation for Global Experiences Toolkit (PDF) Faculty Development Bulletin Faculty Membership
Faculty Programs & Resources Faculty Shortage Faculty Surveys Fair Testing Guidelines (PDF) Fellows Fellowship Dues Find Your NLN ID Foundation for Nursing Education Future of Nursing Report
Gerontology Giving to the NLN Foundation Global Toolkit Grants, Research Hallmarks of Excellence Healthful Work Environment Tool Kit High Stakes Testing (PDF) International Council of Nurses
Informatics Tool Kit Institute for Simulation and Technology Institute for the Care of Vulnerable Populations IOM Report
Jobs Join NLN - Individuals Join NLN - Organizations Journal LEAD Program Leadership Institute Malone Bio Manage Programs Master's Education Member Directory - Associate Members Member Directory - Individuals Member Directory - Member Schools/Agencies Member Engagement Member Login Member Profile Membership Membership Card Member Update Mission and Goals NCSBN Simulation Study NERC News Releases Newsletters NLN Ambassadors NLN Awards NLN Nursing EDge NLN On Demand
NLN The NLN Report
NLN Vision Series Nurse Workforce Development
Nursing Education Competencies Nursing Education Perspectives Nursing Education Policy Online Courses Practical Nursing Education Press Releases
Professional Development Professional Development Bulletin Public Policy
Publications
Toolkits Recognition Programs Refund and Privacy Policy Renew Membership
Research Data Research Grants Research Priorities Research Tools Scholarships Scholarly Writing Retreats Senior Deans and Directors Leadership Program Simulation Education Workshops Simulation Innovation Resource Center SIRC SIRC Courses Staff List Summit
Surveys Teaching Resources Technology Testing Services Teaching Toolkits Transformational Leadership, NLN Center for Update Your Personal Info Veterans Vision Series vSIM Vulnerable Populations Webinars Who to Contact Workshops
Member Login
About
Calendar
Newsroom
Bookstore
Foundation
Contact Us
My Account
NLN Center for Transformational Leadership
NLN Chamberlain University College of Nursing Center for the Advancement of the Science of Nursing Education
Certification for Nurse Educators
CNE®
CNE®cl
Getting Involved
Board Recognition
Certification Sentinel
Home About Privacy Policy
About
Our Commitment to Member and Customer Privacy
The National League for Nursing ("NLN", "we", "us" or "our") is committed to protecting your privacy and personal information. This policy ("Privacy Policy") describes how we collect, use, share, process, and protect your personal information when you use NLN products, services, content, features, software and our website (collectively, "Services"). We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy carefully so that you understand how we address these important issues.
Types of Information Collected Information that you provide
NLN collects information from you during business transactions undertaken on the NLN website or otherwise in connection with your use of the Services. Most commonly, this includes, but is not limited to, joining NLN as a member, registering for a workshop or webinar, registering for the CNE® or CNE®cl exam, or making a purchase through the NLN Marketplace. Such collected information may include, but is not limited to, the following:
Your name, address, phone number, and email address; Your credit or debit card information, information about your bank account and other banking information provided to process a payment whenever you make a purchase; Your location data, such as a location derived from your IP address or data such as a postcode or name of a town or city; Your communications with us, such as a note or recording of a call you make to one of our customer service centers, an email or letter sent, or other records of any contact with us; and Your account information, such as payment data, subscriptions you use, membership status, meeting attendance, account numbers or other information related to your account.
Information that may be collected automatically
When you access or use the Services, we may automatically collect certain information, which may include, but is not limited to, the following:
Unique device identifier assigned to your device; Anonymous identifiers; Your IP address; Location data (e.g., ZIP code, GPS-based location information, longitude/latitude, etc.); and
Other information regarding your access to or use of the Services, which may, among other things, assist us in authenticating your usage or device, keeping track of your preferences, and creating a more tailored user experience.
How We Use Your Information
We use the information you provide to us and the information we collect automatically to improve the Services and your experience with the NLN website. If you are joining NLN as a member, your email may be used to send you member-related updates, newsletters, and pertinent organizational news about member elections, upcoming product releases, and opportunities to engage and volunteer in various capacities. We may also have features that allow you to submit information, questions or feedback to us. In those instances, we may retain your messages, emails, and other information you submit to us for our internal purposes, and to help us, our service providers, partners, collaborators, affiliates, or other third parties serve you better.
We may use your information for, among other things, the following purposes:
Providing any information, services or products that you request, or may be interested in or purchasing on or through the Services; Contacting you regarding the administration of any features or functions of the Services; Sending you marketing, promotional, and other messages and notifications;
Allowing you to participate in the support and other features of the Services; Responding to your questions or other requests; Tailoring your experience with the Services and otherwise customizing what you see when you use the Services; Saving your user account, registration, and profile data or other information so you are not required to have to re-enter it each time you use or access the Services; Storing your user account, registration, and profile data or other information in the event that you terminate your user account or discontinue its use, so that you can restore your user account more easily; Where you order information, products, or services, performing credit checking or other authentication where relevant; Payment processing for such orders; For the prevention and detection of fraud or infringement of our or any third party's rights; Tracking your use of the Services; To comply with legal obligations or legal process; and For any other purposes described in this Privacy Policy or disclosed at the time you provide us with the information or which are reasonably necessary to provide the Services or other related information, product or service requested.
In addition, we may use your information for, among other things, the following purposes:
For research purposes, marketing, or promotional purposes and to provide aggregate or de-identified data for our partners, collaborators, third party organizations, and other similar entities; Collecting and reporting aggregate, statistical information in connection with the Services and user activity; and Determining which features and functionalities of the Services are popular to help us operate the Services, enhance and improve the Services, and display advertising and marketing information.
EXPRESS CONSENT AND AGREEMENT
BY ACCESSING OR USING THE SERVICES, WHETHER AS A REGISTERED USER OR OTHERWISE, YOU EXPRESSLY ACKNOWLEDGE, UNDERSTAND, AND HEREBY AGREE THAT YOU ARE GIVING US YOUR CONSENT TO MONITOR YOUR USE OF THE SERVICES AS DESCRIBED IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY.
Disclosure of Any Information to Third Parties
We reserve the right to use, share and exchange any of your information with affiliates, service providers, and other third parties for any lawful purpose, including, but not limited to, as may otherwise be described above under "How We Use Your Information," and your access to or use of the Services will be deemed your express, affirmative "opt in" consent to the foregoing. We also share information to fight spam, threats, abuse, or infringement activities, and promote safety and security.
Marketing and Promotional Communications
From time to time, you may be presented with the option of whether to receive, or you may be automatically entered to receive, certain marketing, promotional or other communications from us and others that we think will be of interest to you. You can unsubscribe from such communications by either following the specific instructions included in such communications or you may "opt out" of receiving certain marketing and promotional emails from us by sending an email to us at unsubscribe@nln.org detailing your privacy request. Please note that "opt out" and "unsubscribe" requests may not take effect immediately and may take a reasonable amount of time to receive, process and apply, during which time your information will remain subject to the prior privacy settings. Additionally, you should be aware that any information provided to third parties prior to your election to opt out or unsubscribe cannot be retrieved or rescinded by us unless required by applicable law, and you cannot retroactively opt out or unsubscribe with respect to such third parties. Further, please note that notwithstanding any "opt out" or "unsubscribe" request, in order to keep you informed about the operation of the Services, we may always send you emails, notifications, and announcements that are needed for the proper functioning and administration of the Services, including, but not limited to, for the purposes described above under "How We Use Your Information."
Third Party Links
NLN partners with, or holds licenses from, other companies to develop and deliver its products and services to you. The NLN website contains links to these external third party websites which have separate and independent privacy policies. Please be sure to read that company's privacy and cookies policies before using or putting your information on their site. The same applies to any third party websites or content you connect to using our products and services. NLN is not responsible for the data managed and contained on third party servers.
You may choose to disclose your information in certain ways such as social plug-ins (including, but not limited to, those offered by Facebook, Twitter, and LinkedIn) or using third party services that allow you to post reviews or other information publicly, and a third party could use that information. Social plug-ins and social applications are operated by the social network themselves and are subject to their own terms of use and privacy and cookies policies.
Cookies
NLN uses cookies and related technology to analyze website traffic. Cookies assist in personalizing your online experience, simplifying subsequent website visits, and helping to remember certain information about your browser and your information. This allows NLN to better facilitate our electronic communications with you. Cookies are small text files that are placed on your hard drive by a web page. Cookies are unique and can only be read by the issuing domain's web server. Most browsers automatically accept cookies but you can modify your browser to decline using cookies. This, however, may limit your experience of any interactive features of the website you visit.
Website Security
No electronic storage or data transmission over the Internet is 100% secure. While we implement physical, electronic and procedural safeguards designed to protect your information, regardless of our efforts, it is possible that third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions, information or private communications. Accordingly, we cannot guarantee or warrant the security of the information collected in connection with the Services.
You should take steps to protect against unauthorized access to your device by, among other things, choosing a robust password that others do not know and cannot easily guess, and keeping your password private. We are not responsible for any activity on your account via unauthorized password activity or unauthorized access to your device.
Age
We do not knowingly collect information from individuals under 13 years of age. No information should be submitted to or otherwise made available on or through the Services by individuals under 13 years of age.
UK and EU Rights
General
Under UK and EU law, UK and EU users may have certain additional privacy rights, such as the right to lodge a complaint with data protection regulators. The Information Commissioners' Office ("ICO") is the UK's lead regulator. You can find out how to raise a concern with the ICO by visiting their website at www.ico.org.uk. If you're within the EU, you may also get in touch with your local Data Protection Regulator who may liaise with the ICO on your behalf.
Advertising; Other Uses of Personal Data
We may use material that you post on the open access areas of the Services in advertising and promotional materials on our partner sites and partner products. We believe these uses are in line with our legitimate interests in enabling us to improve our Services and better tailor your online experience to meet your needs. If we intend to do this, we will contact you for your prior approval. We use your personal data to resolve disputes and troubleshoot problems.
Legal Basis for Processing Personal Data
For users subject to UK or EU law, the following chart describes our legal basis, in each instance, for processing your personal data:
Purpose for which data is used Data Legal Basis
To provide you with the Services Name, email address, date of birth, age, phone number, location Contractual necessity
To verify your identity and prevent fraud and to ensure the safety and security of users Phone number Legitimate interests – it is in our legitimate interests to ensure that accounts are not set up fraudulently and to safeguard users of the Services
To take payment for fee-based services Payment card details Contractual necessity and legitimate interests – we have a legitimate interest in receiving payment for our fee-based services
To serve targeted advertisements to users of the Services Demographic and location information Legitimate interests – it is in our legitimate interests to target advertisements so that users see relevant advertisements and to allow us to generate income from advertising revenue
To send you marketing information about our offers and services Email address, phone number, other account information Legitimate interests – it is in our legitimate interests to promote our products and services
To carry out research and analysis to help us improve the Services Log and usage data, including IP address, traffic statistics, clickstream data and search terms Legitimate interests – it is in our interests to analyze the way in which users are accessing and using our services so that we can further develop and improve the Services
To respond to correspondence and queries that you submit to us Phone number, account information, email address and IP address Legitimate interests – it is in our legitimate interests to respond to your queries to ensure that we provide a good service to users and troubleshoot problems
Your California Rights
If you are a resident of the State of California, we provide you with information on how to exercise your disclosure choice options such as your right to opt out (which we may sometimes refer to as "unsubscribe") with respect to use of your personal information by third parties for marketing purposes. Therefore, pursuant to the California Civil Code, we are not required to maintain or disclose a list of the third parties that received your personal information for marketing purposes during the preceding year. If you are a California resident and wish to request information about how to exercise your third party disclosure choices, please send a request by email to unsubscribe@nln.org detailing your privacy request. All requests must be labeled "Your California Privacy Rights" on the email subject line. For all requests, please clearly state that the request is related to "Your California Privacy Rights" and include your name, street address, city, state, ZIP code and email address (your street address is optional if you wish to receive a response to your request via email) and indicate your preference on how our response to your request should be sent (email or postal mail). We will not accept requests via phone, postal mail, or by fax. We are not responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent properly, or do not have complete or legible information.
Changes to this Privacy
From time to time, we may amend this Privacy Policy in our sole discretion. In addition to posting any amended Privacy Policy publicly on the NLN website, we may also, to the extent required by applicable law, distribute amended terms directly to users of the Services. Your failure to terminate your user account following any such amendment shall constitute your acceptance of the Privacy Policy as amended. It is therefore important that you review this Privacy Policy regularly to ensure you are aware of any changes.
Accuracy of Your Information
It is your responsibility to give us current, complete, truthful, and accurate information, including with respect to personal information, and to keep such information up to date. We cannot and will not be responsible for any problems or liability that may arise if you do not give us complete, truthful, or accurate information or you fail to update such information. We may reject and delete any information that we believe in good faith to be false, fraudulent, or inconsistent with this Privacy Policy.
International Usage
While the Services are intended for use within the United States, the Services are also accessible outside of the United States. By using the Services, you acknowledge that: (i) if you live in a country with data protection laws, the privacy laws of the United States may not provide you with the same protections as you enjoy in your country of residence; and (ii) if you visit, access, interact with or otherwise use the Services from a location outside the United States, any information you provide in connection with any such activity may be processed in or transferred to the United States or other territories and locations, where privacy protections may not be as comprehensive as those in the territory or location where you interact with or otherwise use the Services. By using the Services, you affirmatively consent to the transfer, use, storage, processing, disclosure, provision, and other administration of your information in the United States and as described herein.
Sole Statement
This document is the sole statement of the Privacy Policy for the Services and no summary, restatement or other version thereof, or other privacy statement or policy, in any form, including, but not limited to, machine-generated, is valid.
This Privacy Policy was last modified on June 21, 2019, and is effective as of that date.
Share This Page
About
Calendar
Newsroom
Bookstore
Foundation
Contact Us
My Account
Certification for Nurse Educators
The Watergate | 2600 Virginia Avenue, NW | Eighth Floor | Washington, DC 20037 | 800-669-1656 Copyright © 2014 National League for Nursing The Voice for Nursing Education
